Alan Guerrero

Senior Frontend Web and Smart Contract Developer

- ™ Tunki1201@gmail.com
- **** +1 713 636 5780
- 9 18203 Kiker Road Winnie, TX
- https://github.com/Tunki1201
- S live:.cid.c06827bfe523ff0a
- **1** 01/12/1995
- https://tunki1201.github.io/



Profile

Senior Frontend Web and Smart Contract Developer with 10+ years of experience developing useful, approachable user interfaces. Knowledgeable on all aspects of Facebook's design best practices and emerging UI development techniques.

Skilled at connecting exceptional assets with users via creative UI frameworks and careful user experience optimization. Brings both cuttingedge programming expertise and exceptional interpersonal skills

Professional Experience

02/2021 – 05/2023

Grosvenor Rd, Ripley DE5 3JE, UK

Senior Frontend and Smart Contract Developer, JHC Security LTD

- Developed the \$Frost token, APR NFT and Reward generated NFT, and NFT Migration contract on BSC chain
- Built the NFT Migration landing pages and Staking pages with React and Reduxsaga
- Used css framework SCSS
- Implemented the web3 integration by using web3.js, ethers.js, and Alchemy API
- Scrapped the token info (token nomics id, market capital price, etc) with coingeko, tryroll, and Moralis API by using token event scheduler.

08/2019 - 02/2021

Marina Boulevard, Singapore

Senior Web3 Frontend Developer, Capgemini Singapore Pte. Ltd.

- Brought in shipping confidence for the app and improved our deployment pipeline by implementing a testing harness in Jest and Enzyme covering over 75% of client code, configuringlinting with ESLint and formatting with Prettier for overall code quality.
- Worked on Web3 integration using ethers.js and web3.js
- Used Redux toolkit for state management
- Proceeded the wallet connection, token swapping, balance checking, token approved transaction, market order and limit order with 0xAPI
- Enforced Agile and Scrum development methodologies on interface projects to shorten development times.

08/2016 - 08/2019

Mapletree Business City, Singapore

Senior Frontend Developer, Terato Tech

- Built the website same as Figma design with Pixel Perfect and UI/UX.
- Translating client requirements into clean, reliable, and maintainable codes.
- Monitoring performance gaps and identifying errors in user experience before they appear.
- Integrated the payment system with Stripe.
- Worked with google map APIs and Doordash APIs.
- Integrated with Twilio and Sendgrid email services
- Worked in CI/CD environment (Jira pipelined with slack, Jenkins automatic testing system, Dock deployment).

Alan Guerrero 1/2

- Optimized and improved the code quality by owning the rewriting of the application from an MVC view- based approach to a SPA, rewriting all class-based components to functional components with hooks, implemented the Context API for global storage and authored over 330 individual tests across 110 test suites to react 80% code coverage.
- Rewrite the code with Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and Typescript

07/2013 – 08/2016

Mapletree Business city, Singapore

Frontend Developer, SAP Asia Pte Ltd.

- Expertise in HTML, CSS, and SPA frameworks.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies.
- Participated in cross-functional projects while working in lean development environments.
- Familiar with using the Styled Component, Tailwind CSS, and SASS/SCSS
- Implemented the chart with D3.js and Armchart for viewing the data
- Developed end-end testing by using Cypress, and Cucumber
- Developed the mobile apps RWRD coffee shop app and Tila Musing with React Native
- Design the REST calls and implemented them with Axios or Fetch
- Design the graphQL queries and mutations by using Apollo GraphQL(client)

Skills

Languages

Javascript, Node.js, Typescript

Frontend

React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Tailwind CSS, SASS/SCSS, Styled Component, Material UI/MUI, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Vuetify, jQuery, Redux(saga, toolkit, thunk), Vuex, Jest, Cypress, Cucumber, Axios, Apollo GraphQL, gRPC, D3.js, ChartJS, Armchart, ThreeJS, PixiJS, PhaserJS, websocket

Backend Development

Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Ruby on Rails, Codelgniter, Laravel, Django, Spring boot, Flask, RESTful APIs, SOAP

Cryptography

Symmetric Cryptography, Asymmetric Cryptography, Digital Signature, Authentication, Attacks model

Web3 Frameworks

web3.js, ethers.js, web3-react, Moralis API, Alchemy API

Smart Contract

Solidity, Hardhat, Truffle, Remix, Openzepllin

DevOps

AWS, JIRA, Azure, Git, CI/CD, Hasura, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, Jenkins

Education

08/2011 - 08/2016

California, United States Bachelor's degree of Computer Science, University of Southern California

Alan Guerrero 2/2